Mike North: 那么让我们来看一下变量声明和初始化的分离。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So let's look at separating
variable declarations and initializations.
所以，我们经常需要这样做。
So, often, we need to do this.
我能想到的我做这件事的一个地方就是
One place I can think of
that I do this is if I have
根据某些条件取不同值的变量。
a variable that takes on a different
value based on some conditions.
也许我有一个大小写切换包含五个或六个大小写条款
Maybe I have a case switch with five or
six case clauses, and
我想根据这些条款来设定某物的价值。
I wanna set the value of something based
on which of those clauses I fall into.
我可能会在 switch 语句外面声明这个变量,
I'll probably declare that variable
outside of the switch statement,
然后分配给每个子句。
and then assign it in each of the clauses.
所以你最终会得到这样的东西，但是
So you end up with something like this,
but
我们遇到了一些麻烦事。
we run into something that looks
a little bit troubling here.
我们将它初始化为41或者重新分配给41，因为它没有初始化式。
We initialize it to 41 or reassign
it to 41 cuz it has no initializer.
然后看起来我们也可以用一个字符串。
And then it looks like we
can use a string as well.
这给了我们一个线索，关于这里发生了什么。
And this gives us a clue as to what's
going on here, z takes on a type of any.
这基本上是一张万能牌。
It's basically a wildcard.
类型系统，一般来说，称之为 top 类型。
Well, type systems, in general,
call this a top type.
Top 类型可以取任何值。
Top types can take any value.
并不是说这些都是邪恶的。
And it's not that these are evil.
它们只是遵循 JavaScript 变量所遵循的规则,
They just play by the same rules
that JavaScript variables play by,
我们可以在字符串、数字、数组和函数之间切换,
where we can flip-flop between strings,
and numbers, and arrays, and functions,
你想怎样就怎样。
and it'll take on whatever you want.
所以这是你们这类人的弱点。
So it's a point of weakness in your types.
现在，有些地方完全可以使用 any，所以
Now, there are places where it's
totally valid to use an any, so
别以为你的任务就是把他们从你的应用程序里清除。
don't think that you're on a mission
to completely purge them from your app.
你只是想确保无论你在哪里,
You just wanna make sure
that wherever you have it,
你真的想让任何事情。
you actually want to allow
absolutely anything.
迈克 · 诺斯: 所以如果我们愿意的话，我们可以改善情况,
&gt;&gt; Mike North: So we could improve
the situation if we wanted to by,
在变量声明中，指定一个类型。
in our variable declaration,
specifying a type.
这被称为类型注释。
And this is called a type annotation.
我们附加了一些额外的信息
We're sort of attaching a little
extra piece of information
你没有初始值设定项,
to the variable that says, look,
you don't have an initializer,
但我告诉你，数字才是你设计的目的。
but I'm telling you number is
what you're designed to hold.
现在我们得到了我们想要的类型错误，如果我们试图把一个字符串放入这个变量。
And now we get our desirable type error if
we try to put a string into this variable.
所以这就是你要小心的地方，对吗？
So this is something you
gotta watch out for, right?
如果声明中没有初始化变量,
If you have declarations where you
don't initialize the variable,
你要说明这是什么型号的。
you're gonna wanna specify what
type this is designed to hold.
什么事？
Yes?
演讲者2: 所以在 TypesScript 的官方文档中，他们通常会这么做
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: So in the official docs of
TypesScript, they generally do do that
类型声明，即使使用值初始化变量。
type declaration, even if you're
initializing the variable with a value.
建议这样做还是不建议，或者现在重要吗？
Is it recommended to do it that way or
no, or does it now matter?
迈克 · 诺斯: 这是个很好的问题。
&gt;&gt; Mike North: That's a great question.
如果你正在写文档，我建议你这么做
I would say it's recommended to do that
way if you are writing docs because you
在文档中非常具有描述性。
are being very descriptive
in documentation.
而且,
And what's more,
我相信打字稿团队会很高兴能够展示工具提示
I'm sure the TypeScript team would love
to have the ability to show tool tips
在他们的医生里，你可以在那里徘徊，看看他们是什么，对吗？
in their docs where you could hover over
things and see what they are, right?
就像这个例子一样,
So like in this example up here,
描述这是类型 hello world，喜欢写在文本上,
describing that this is of type hello
world, like to write that out on text,
为了描述的目的，这样做可能有点冗长。
you might be verbose in doing so
for descriptive purposes.
但是因为我们这里有一个编辑，我们不必这样做。
But because we have an editor here,
we don't have to do that.
我宁愿在一些特定的地方提供类型信息。
I err on the side of providing type
information in a few specific places.
带有初始化器的变量,
Variables with initializers,
不是这些地方，因为打字稿总是可以推断出那个位置。
not one of those places because TypeScript
can always infer at that location.
现在，我将非常清楚地指出我总是放置类型信息的地方
Now, I'll be very clear to point out
spots where I always put type information
作为一种在代码片段之间设置有意识界限的方式。
as a way of kind of setting deliberate
boundaries around pieces of code.
基本上，当我提供类型信息时，我要做的就是
Basically, what I'm trying to do
when I provide type information
在两个事物之间提供一个明确的契约
is provide an explicit contract
between two things, and
在合同的两边都保持诚实。
keep myself honest on both
sides of that contract.
但是在这里，它只是一些额外的东西。
But here,
it would sort of just be extra stuff.
但是我会用同样的方式来写我的文档。
But I would write my docs in
the same way to be clear.